Aaron Hilado

UX/UI Designer

Focused UX/UI Designer, skilled in Sketch, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop and UX research. Works well as an individual, as well as in teams maintaining strong communication, and able to take a lead position if necessary. Able to define and understand user and business needs to create an experience that revolves around said needs in order to improve user experience and business sales.

Education

University of California, Irvine Division of Continuing Education

November 2017 - May 2018 | Irvine, CA

Certification, UX/UI Design

University of California, Irvine

September 2013 - June 2017 | Irvine, CA Bachelor of the Arts, Art

Work Experience

Freelance UX/UI Designer

Aug 2018 - Present

- Identify user needs and goals and build products that are centered around the user
- Design UI mockups, wireframes, and prototypes and conduct user testing of design solutions
- Ideate solutions that help solve a problem/goal while maintaining visual aesthetic

Uniqlo South Coast Plaza

Division Advisor | Aug 2016 - Sept 2019

Worked as a part of the management team maintaining strong communication with upper management and store associates to collaborate and make sure store operations run smoothly and work efficiency is optimized.

☐ (626) 977 0822 amhilado.github.io/AHiladoSite aaronh1194@gmail.com

Skills

Rapid Prototyping, Wireframing,
UI Design, Style Guides, Color Theory,
Responsive Web Design, Sitemaps,
User-Centered Design, User Research,
User Personas, Storyboarding,
Usability Testing, Experience
Maps, User Journeys, Affinity
Diagrams, Agile Design Methodology

Tools

HTML5, CSS3, Sketch, InVision, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Premiere, GitHub, GitKraken, Visual Studio Code

Selected Projects

ArtsOC Website Redesign

Performed brainstorming, wireframe sketching, and design of low and high fidelity prototypes of the homepage. Helped conduct primary research and helped develop a user journey based off of the research. Devised and implemented a style guide to be used throughout the website.

NSA Website Redesign

Produced a style guide that aligns with the NSA's values. Performed User Interface Design and redesigned top navigation to improve user experience. Redesigned layout and changed typeface to improve readability.

Bookmmunity (Barnes and Noble App Design)

Conducted user interview, produced user persona, and user journey. Sketched wireframe and designed low fidelity prototype to test design solutions. Designed high fidelity prototype to incorporate more visual design elements, such as images, icons, and a color palette.

Canabru Website Redesign

Sketched wireframes and designed low fidelity prototypes to test features and design ideas. Performed ideation, interface design, and developed a responsive web prototype using HTML and CSS.